1. Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

  4 minute read  

**Last updated: May 15, 2023**

This SelfPrivacy (“SelfPrivacy” or “we” or “us” or “our”) privacy policy (the “**Privacy Policy**”) is designed to help you understand what information we collect, including information that directly or indirectly identifies an individual (“personal information”), and how we use or share that information.

We take your privacy very seriously, and we are committed to ensuring that your personal information is kept safe and secure. This Privacy Policy explains how we manage your personal information when you use our application.

We want to keep it simple, and we don’t want to hide behind long paragraphs of text, small lines or difficult words.

SelfPrivacy is an open-source project. Please note that we are neither the data controller nor the data processor for any data processing operations carried out through our application. We do not have control over how users utilize the application or how they process any data that they may choose to host or store through the application. As such, we cannot be held responsible for any data processing activities carried out by our users. We encourage all users to carefully consider their data processing activities and to comply with applicable data protection laws and regulations.

Collection of Information
-------------------------

Our application does not collect any personal information from you. We do not collect your name, email address, or any other contact information. We also do not collect any technical information about your device, including your IP address, operating system, or browser type.

SelfPrivacy does not collect limited service and usage data like error and diagnostics information, security alerts, and log file reports associated with device identifiers. We refer to this information as “telemetry data,” and it does not include any end user personal identifiers or message contents.

We collect access logs to determine our user count and the countries they are visiting from. However, we store visitor IP addresses as subnets (x.x.x.0) which may not be sufficient to uniquely identify individuals. Although we cannot guarantee that our server provider does not collect meta-information, we advise users to use methods of traffic anonymization for added privacy.

Tracking
--------

Our application provides users with the necessary tools to create self-hosted services, such as web servers or databases, without requiring them to provide any personal information. We do not track users’ activities or behaviors within the application, and we do not use cookies or other tracking technologies.

Third-party service providers
-----------------------------

We have no control over the personal information that users provide to third-party service providers when opting for self-hosted services. Our application initiates interactions with third-party service providers only after the user has selected them. When users consent to allow third-party service providers to collect and process personal information about their online activities using cookies, pixels, local storage, and other technologies, we are not accountable for the privacy practices of these third parties. This Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of these third parties.

Use of Information
------------------

Since we do not collect any personal information from you, we cannot use it for any purpose. Our application is designed to allow you to set up and use self-hosted services without the need for any personal information. We do not use your information for marketing purposes.

Disclosure of Information
-------------------------

Since we do not collect any personal information from you, we cannot disclose it to anyone. We do not share your personal information with any third parties.

Protection of Information
-------------------------

We take the security of your personal information very seriously. Even though we do not collect any personal information about you, we still use industry-standard security measures to protect our application and the data it contains. We use encryption, firewalls, and other security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

Changes to this Privacy Policy
------------------------------

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our practices or to comply with legal requirements. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy regularly to stay informed about how we collect, use, and protect your personal information.

Contact Us
----------

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or the collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, please contact us at `privacy@selfprivacy.org`. We will do our best to address your concerns in a timely and satisfactory manner.

* * *

_We are pleased to offer this Privacy Policy under Creative Commons Zero license as a template that can be used by anyone in the open-source community. We hope that this contribution will help to support the development of privacy policies that promote transparency, accountability, and respect for the privacy of individuals. As part of our commitment to open-source values, we believe in sharing knowledge and resources to foster innovation and collaboration. Therefore, we encourage others to adapt and modify our privacy policy to meet their specific needs, while ensuring that they comply with applicable laws and regulations._

Last modified April 29, 2024: [fix: rename folder (c46e9bb)](https://git.selfprivacy.org/SelfPrivacy/selfprivacy.org/commit/c46e9bb2ac4e022c62252b645ed6ed7327ef1bb9)

Learn more
----------

### Get help

Contribute
----------

Download the app
----------------

### For your phone

### For your computer
